KUMAR KUNAL () Featured

Senior System Engineer seeking roles in Software Development,System Engineering,Digital Asset Management,Configuration Management,Project Management,Change Management,Requirement Gathering,Application Support,JavaScript,jQuery,HTML,CSS,SQL,C,C++



Current Designation: Senior System Engineer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Siemens Healthcare Private Limited. Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior System Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, System Engineering, Digital Asset Management, Change Management, SQL, .Net, MVC, WCF, MVVM, ASP.Net, Winforms, C#, Angular, Web Api, Entity

Framework

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Currently working as a Sr. System Engineer in Siemens Healthcare Private Limited. Having 5 years 8 months of experience.

Have experience in Digital Asset Management ERP and Epicor ERP.

Have experience in Healthcare in Advanced Therapy

Proficient in .NET (C#), Web Api, MVC, WCF, Angular and Microsoft SQL Server.

Work Experience

Siemens Healthcare Private Limited. as Senior System Engineer May 2018 to Till Date

Siemens Healthcare (Since May 18):

Project Title: System Support Function For Advanced Therapy

Contributions:

- 1. Worked on development of core service layer components for the latest generation of Artis systems for Siemens Healthcare in Angiography and X-Ray divison. The software modules were related to Configuration, Calibration, Backup and Restore etc.
- 2. Worked on design and development of state machines for service workflow.
- 3. Development of Service UI using Angular and SignalR.
- 4. Developing Framework to support communication between Service UI and Service Workflow
- 5. Feasibility analysis and definition of subsystem functional requirements for Service software application suite and also overlooking subsystem integration.
- 6. Design and development of an Automation Framework in C# for all the service software components making UI testing more feasible using specflow.
- 7. Proposed a much feasible alternative design (using Factory Design Pattern) for the Configuration module of service software and worked on the refactoring and re-writing of the entire code in a week to show a working module.
- 8. Worked on development of a new feature for service software application of ArtisSoftware to incorporate a NEXT button for workflow navigation which eases the task of the clinical user. Developed(using knowledge ASP.NET and C#) and demonstrated a working demo.

Epicor Software as Technical Consultant

May 2017 to May 2018

Project Title: Manufacturing Domain ERP Development

The project aimed toward developing ERP for Manufacturing domain Industries using Epicor E10

Client:

1. Great Lakes Custom Tool Mfg 2. Janus File Systems

Epicor Professional Skills:

- 1. Business Activity Query
- 2. Embedded Customization
- 3. Business Process Management
- 4. Dashboard
- 5. BAQ SSRS Report
- 6. Service Connect
- 7. Epicor SDK

Contributions:

Used Epicor professional skills and Microsoft.Net technology to build ERP for client involved in Manufacturing industries.

Prime Focus Technologies as Software Developer

Aug 2014 to May 2017

Project Title: Content Live 2.0 Migration & Development

The project aimed toward migration of old data and product features, and integrating it with the new product features.

Client: Star India Private Ltd

Contributions:

- 1. Have developed Folder based Window Services for media file upload.
- 2. Have developed several Console Applications and deployed it as a scheduler.
- 3. Have developed Dashboards using Web Forms, AJAX, Javascript, CSS, Web Services, WCF and MSSQL Server Database.
- 4. Integrated open source tool (Lucene search and Elastic search) in development of media asset library search.
- 5. Designing workflow for managing client business processes.
- 6. SSRS and Excel Application report development.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Heritage Institute of Technology, Kolkata in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C#, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript	
JQuery, SQL, Angular, Web Services, WCF	
ADO.NET, SSRS, LINQ, Visual Studio	
Microsoft SQL Server, Windows	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time